Register to the Papers of Kurt Weill and Lotte Lenya
Yale University Music Library
- Music by Weill, 1913-1983; Series I; 23.3' (41 boxes)
  - Operas, Operettas, Musicals, and Ballets, I.A
    - [Zar lässt sich photographieren (Sketches)], [16] p. of music; 35 cm. R. 14, Fr. 300-309. (Box 33, Folder 447)
      See also: C. Theater and Radio Scores. Gustav III (Sketches).
    - [Zaubernacht. Piano score (Sketches)], [1922].; 1 piano score (68 [i.e. 66] p.); 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 310-344. (Box 33, Folder 448)
      Holograph in ink with pencil and crayon additions.
      "Pages 65-66 have been removed" - David Drew.
      See also: D. Orchestral. Quodlibet.
  - Film scores, I.B
    - [Common glory (Sketches)], [1938].; 3 p. of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 346-347. (Box 33, Folder 449)
      Begins: Almighty and everlasting God...
    - [One touch of Venus (Sketches)], [1945-1948] [David Drew].; [8] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 348-352. (Box 33, Folder 450)
      Holographs in ink.
      Includes: '"The Picture on the wall," with lyrics by Ann Ronnell' - David Drew.
    - [River is blue (Sketches)], [1937 Mar.-Apr.] [David Drew].; [4] p. of music; 37 cm. R. 14, Fr. 353-355. (Box 33, Folder 451)
      Unused music for a film by Lewis Milestone, screenplay by Clifford Odets.
      Written in blue ink on the first p.: "The River is Blue."
    - [River is blue (Sketches)], [1937 Mar.-Apr.] [David Drew].; [4] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 356-358. (Box 33, Folder 451)
    - [River is blue (Sketches)], [1937 Mar.-Apr.] [David Drew].; [12] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 359-365. (Box 33, Folder 451)
      In ink on first p.: "Film (Where do we go from here?)."
      See also: You and me (Sketches).
    - [Salute to France. Chant de la libération; arr. (Sketches)], [1944 Apr.-May] [David Drew].; [I] sheet of music; 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 366. (Box 33, Folder 452)
      Arrangement of song with music and text by Anna Marly.
      See also: III. MUSIC BY OTHERS. MARLY, Anna. Chant de la libération.
    - [Salute to France (Sketches)], [6] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 367-371. (Box 33, Folder 452)
      Score to film by Jean Renoir and Garson Kanin, script by Maxwell Anderson.
    - [Salute to France (Sketches)], [10] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 372-382. (Box 33, Folder 452)
      See also: H. Arrangements. [Renard, Antoine]. Temps des cerises; arr. English.
    - [Where do we go from here?], 1 score ([102] p. in various pagings); 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 383-438. (Box 33, Folder 453)
      Contents: No. 1. Opening: a) That's how it is; b) Telephone passage; and c) Morale (25 p., sketch at end). No. 2. All at once ([3] p.). No. 3. It could have happened to anyone (4 p.). No. 4. If love remains (8 p.). No. 5. Song of the Rhineland (13 p.). Columbus (40 p.). Woo, woo, woo, woo, Manhattan (6 p.). Theme for Cuban music in Columbus sequence ([1] sheet). Theme for church scene in Dutch sequence ([2] p.).
    - [Where do we go from here? All at once; arr.] All at once: fox trot / music by Kurt Weill; lyrics by Ira Gershwin; orch. by Jack Mason. - New York: Chappell, c1945., 15 parts; 28 cm. (Box 33, Folder 454)
      Arr. for piano, trumpet I-III, trombone I-II, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, violin A-C, double bass, percussion, and guitar.
    - [Where do we go from here? All at once. Vocal score] All at once / music by Kurt Weill; words by Ira Gershwin. - New York: Chappell, c1945., 1 vocal score (5 p.); 30 cm. (Box 33, Folder 454)
      Composed in 1943-1944.
      Pl. no.: 1358-4.
    - [Where do we go from here? If love remains. Text], [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 33, Folder 454)
      Typescript (carbon copy).
    - [Where do we go from here? If love remains. Vocal score] If love remains / music by Kurt Weill; words by Ira Gershwin. - New York: Chappell, c1945., 1 vocal score (7 p.); 30 cm. (Box 33, Folder 454)
      Pl. no.: 1363-5.
    - [Where do we go from here? Nina, the Pinta, the Santa Maria. Vocal score] Nina, the Pinta, the Santa Maria / music by Kurt Weill; words by Ira Gershwin. - New York: Chappell, c1954., 1 vocal score (13 p.); 31 cm. (Box 33, Folder 454)
      Pl. no.: 2044-11.
    - [Where do we go from here (Sketches)], [30] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 439-468. (Box 33, Folder 455)
    - [Where do we go from here (Sketches)], [58] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 469-500. (Box 33, Folder 455)
      Holographs in pencil and ink.
    - [Where do we go from here (Sketches)], [4] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 501-503. (Box 33, Folder 455)
    - [Where do we go from here? Song of the Rhineland. Vocal score] Song of the Rhineland / music by Kurt Weill; words by Ira Gershwin. - New York: Chappell, c1945., 1 vocal score (7 p.); 30 cm. (Box 33, Folder 456)
      Pl. no.: 1364-6.
    - [You and me. Barbershop-Quartet. Vocal score] Barbershop-Quartet / music by Kurt Weill; words by Sam Coslow., 1 vocal score ([4] p.); 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 504-506. (Box 33, Folder 457)
      Music for film directed by Fritz Lang.
      Composed: "April-June 1937 / December 1937 / Spring 1938" - David Drew.
    - [You and me. Jiggaboo (Sketches)] Jiggaboo, / Kurt Weill., [2] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 506-507. (Box 33, Folder 457)
      Holograph signed, in pencil.
    - [You and me. Knocking song. Vocal score] Knocking song / music by Kurt Weill; words by Sam Coslow., 1 vocal score (9 p.); 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 507-511. (Box 33, Folder 457)
      Stamp on bottom of first page: Dee 22 1937.
      "First version" - David Drew.
    - [You and me. Knocking song. Vocal score] Knocking song: (from "You and me") / Kurt Weill; Sam Coslow., 1 vocal score ([13] p.); 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 512-520. (Box 33, Folder 457)
      "Second version" - David Drew.
      Sketch for Knickerbocker Holiday on back. [David Drew].
    - [You and me. Knocking song. Vocal score] Knocking song / by Kurt Weill., 1 vocal score (33 p.); 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 520-537. (Box 33, Folder 457)
      Manuscript in ink and holograph in pencil.
      "A copyist's score of the second version is prefaced by the autograph sketch of a 9-bar 'knocking rhythm' for six pitched and three (or more) unpitched percussion" - David Drew.
    - [You and me. Knocking song. Vocal score (Sketches)], [2] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 538-539. (Box 33, Folder 457)
      Arrangement for voice ("Big Shot") and chorus.
    - [You and me. Knocking song. Vocal score (Sketches)], [1] sheet of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 540. (Box 33, Folder 457)
      Includes jottings re percussion.
    - [You and me. Knocking song. Vocal score (Sketches)], [1] sheet of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 541. (Box 33, Folder 457)
    - [You and me. Right guy for me. Vocal score] Right guy for me., 1 vocal score ([5] p.); 17-32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 542-544. (Box 33, Folder 457)
      Words only partially included.
    - [You and me. Right guy for me. Vocal score] Right guy for me., 1 vocal score ([5] p.); 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 545-547. (Box 33, Folder 457)
    - [You and me. Right guy for me. Vocal score] Right guy for me., 1 vocal score ([2] sheets); 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 548. (Box 33, Folder 457)
      Holograph in pencil, title in another hand in red pencil.
      "The third (final) version" - David Drew.
    - [You and me. Right guy for me. Vocal score] Right guy for me / Kurt Weill; Sam Coslow., 1 vocal score (5 p.); 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 549-551. (Box 33, Folder 457)
      "Fair copy" - David Drew.
    - [You and me. Right guy for me. Vocal score] Right guy for me / words and music by Sam Coslow & Kurt Weill. - New York: Famous Music Corporation, c1938., 1 vocal score (7 p.); 31 cm. R. 14, Fr. 552-555. (Box 33, Folder 457)
    - [You and me. Romance of a lifetime. Text] Romance of a lifetime / music: Kurt Weill; lyric: Sam Coslow., [1] sheet; 28 cm. R. 14, Fr. 558. (Box 33, Folder 457)
      In ink at end: "Music at Harms belongs to L. Lenya."
    - [You and me. Romance of a lifetime. Vocal score] Romance of a lifetime / music by Kurt Weill; words by Sam Coslow., 1 vocal score ([4] p.); 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 555-557. (Box 33, Folder 457)
    - [You and me. Selections. Vocal score], 1 vocal score ([38] p.); 32 cm. (Box 33, Folder 458)
      Manuscript in copyist's hand with pencil additions (photocopies).
      Contents: Song of the cash register / Kurt Weill; Sam Coslow; Phil Boutelse. - 1938 May 4 (7 p., 2 copies). Five years ain't so long: Knocking scene [Knocking song] / music by Kurt Weill; vocal arr. Max Terr; lyrics by Sam Coslow (14 p., 2 copies), Song of the lie / words by Johnny Burke (5 p., 2 copies). Right guy for me / Kurt Weill; Sam Coslow; devised by Al Siegal; orchestration by Gordon Jenkins. - 1938 Jan. 7 (8 p., 2 copies). We're the kind of people who sing lullabies / lyric by Johnny Burke (4 p.).
      "Recording version" appears on several scores.
    - [You and me (Sketches)], [16] sheets of music; 10-34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 559-573. (Box 33, Folder 459)
    - [You and me (Sketches)], [12] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 574-581. (Box 33, Folder 459)
      Includes a sketch for "Robbery."
      With sketch: "of refrain of 'Der Mädchenraub' (Der Kuhhandel)" - David Drew.
    - [You and me (Sketches)], [10] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 585-590. (Box 33, Folder 459)
    - [You and me (Sketches)], [1] folded sheet ([4] p.) of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 591-593. (Box 33, Folder 459)
      Includes one page of jottings.
    - [You and me (Sketches)], [1] folded sheet ([3] p.) of music; 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 582-584. (Box 33, Folder 459)
      Last side contains sketches for The River is Blue. [David Drew].
    - [You and me. Too much to dream. Vocal score (Sketches)] Too much to dream / music by Kurt Weill; words by Sam Coslow., 1 vocal score ([4] p.); 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 594-596. (Box 33, Folder 460)
  - Theater and Radio Scores, I.C
    - [Flag is born. Condensed score], 1946 Nov. 21.; 1 condensed score ([16] sheets); 37 cm. (Box 33, Folder 461)
      Contents: Opening (6 sheets). Partisan (6 sheets). No. 13. Temple music / music by Kurt Weill; arranged by Isaac Van Grove (3 sheets). #14. Interlude (2 sheets).
    - [Fun to be free. Introduction (Sketches)], [1941] [David Drew].; 7 p. of music; 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 598-601. (Box 33, Folder 461)
      "For narrators, chorus, and orchestra" - David Drew.
      "Pageant by Ben Hecht and Charles MacArthur" - David Drew.
    - Grande complainte de Fantômas
      See: F. Songs. Grande complainte de Fantômas.
    - [Gustav III], 1927 Oct 16-19.; 1 score (39 p.).; 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 602-624. (Box 33, Folder 462)
      Holograph in ink with markings in red pencil and blue crayon.
      Incidental music to play by Strindberg.
      Ink caricature of a conductor (15 x 11 cm.) pasted on.
    - [Gustav III (Sketches)], [14] p. of music; 21 x 30, 37 cm. R. 14, Fr. 625-642. (Box 33, Folder 462)
      Holographs (photocopies).
      Extra copy of portions of 4 of the sheets laid in.
      Copies of originals belonging to O. W. Neighbour, given to the Yale University Music Library in a letter dated 1983 Aug. 10. Copies (not the originals) have been numbered by O. W. Neighbour. This in described in detail on the folder.
      Contains sketches for Mahagonny and Der Zar lässt sich photographieren.
    - Herzog Theodor von Gothland
      See: A. Operas, Operettas, Musicals, and Ballets. Na und (Sketches), [David Drew].
    - [Konjunktur. Muschel von Margate. Vocal score] Muschel von Margate: Petroleum-Song / von Kurt Weill; Text von Felix, [1928 Mar.].; 1 vocal score ([2] sheets); 42 cm. (Box 104, Folder 463)
      Incidental music for play by Leo Lania, song texts by Felix Gasbarra.
    - [Konjunktur], [14] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 643-641. (Box 33, Folder 464)
      Holograph in ink, with pencil manuscript markings in unknown hand.
      Contents: Anfang. Landungsbrücke. Kleiner Marsch. Ollage (Film). Arbeitsrhythmus. Arbeiterlied (1. and 2. Fassung). Muschelsong.
      Alternate pages from [7-13] are stamped: Universal Edition Archiv.
      Page [7] in a torn sheet (17 cm.).
    - [Konjunktur (Sketches)], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 33, Folder 464)
      Contents: II. Akt Nachtszene. Muschelsong. Petroleum-Musik.
    - Lindberghflug
      See: E. Large-scale Vocal. Lindberghflug.
    - [Madam, will you walk], [1939 Nov.]; 9 parts; 29-34 m. R. 14, Fr. 652-687. (Box 33, Folder 465)
      Includes piano, saxophone I-II, trumpet I-II, trombone, double bass, percussion, and novachord parts.
      Also includes 3 positive and 1 negative photostat of the piano part (30 cm.).
    - [Madam, will you walk. Libretto] Madam, will you walk? / by Sidney Howard, 1939 Nov. 1.; 42, 32, 32 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 33, Folder 466)
      "Copyright 1939/Brandt & Brandt Dramatic Department..." - title page.
    - [Madam, will you walk (Sketches)], [5] p. of music; 28 cm. R. 14, Fr. 688-691. (Box 33, Folder 467)
      With: sketch for "Nanna's Lied" on verso of one sheet. [David Drew].
      See also: Operas, Operettas, Musicals, and Ballets. Kingdom for a cow. German (Sketches); and F. Songs. Complainte de la Seine (Sketches). [David Drew].
    - [Marie Galante. Chanson de Soledad] Chanson de Soledad, [1934].; 1 part ([1] sheet); 15 x 25 cm. R. 14, Fr. 692. (Box 34, Folder 468)
      Voice part.
      Composed in 1934 Aug. 27-Sep. [David Drew].
    - [Marie Galante. Chanson de Staub] Chanson de Staub., 1 part ([1] sheet); 25 x 27 cm. R. 14, Fr. 693. (Box 34, Folder 468)
    - [Marie Galante. Chanson de Staub (Sketches)] Chanson de Staub / Kurt Weill., [1] p. of music; 35 cm. R. 14, Fr. 694-695. (Box 34, Folder 468)
      With: ink draft for "Introduction" on back. [David Drew].
    - [Marie Galante. Chant des matelots] Chant des matelots., 1 part ([1] sheet); 17 x 25 cm. R. 14, Fr. 699. (Box 34, Folder 468)
    - Marie Galante. Complainte de la Seine
      See: F. Songs. Complainte de la Seine.
    - [Marie Galante. Les filles de Bordeaux] Marie Galante: Les filles de Bordeaux / musique de Kurt Weill; paroles de Jacques Deval. - Paris: Heugel, c1934., [2] p. of music; 27 cm. R. 14, Fr. 696-698. (Box 34, Folder 468)
      Unaccompanied voice part only.
    - [Marie Galante. Introduction (Sketches)] Introduction Dancing., 1 score ([2] p.); 35 cm. R. 14, Fr. 700-701. (Box 34, Folder 468)
      See also: Marie Galante. Chanson de Staub (Sketches).
    - [Marie Galante. J'attends un navire; arr.] J'attends un navire / Kurt Weill; Jacques Deval, [1942-1943?] [David Drew].; 1 score (6 p.); 32 cm. R. 14, Fr. 702-705. (Box 34, Folder 469)
      An arrangement which Drew notes was "commissioned by Bost Records Inc. for Lotte Lenya."
      No. 6 of Six Songs by Kurt Weill. [David Drew].
    - [Marie Galante. J'attends un navire (Sketches)], [1] sheet of music; 35 cm. R. 14, Fr. 709. (Box 34, Folder 469)
    - [Marie Galante. J'attends un navire (Sketches)], [1] p. of music; 36 cm. R. 14, Fr. 706-708 (Box 34, Folder 469)
      With: signed pencil draft for "Scène au dancing." [David Drew].
      See also: I. Unidentified Sketches.
    - [Marie Galante. Marche de l'armée panaméenne; arr.] Marie Galante: Marche de l'armée panaméenne / Kurt Weill. - Paris: Heugel, c1934., 3 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 34, Folder 470)
      Arrangement for piano.
      Pl. no.: H. 30,911.
    - [Marie Galante. Le roi d'Aquitaine. Vocal score] Roi d'Aquitaine / Kurt Weill, c1934.; 1 vocal score ([3] p.); 36 cm. R. 14, Fr. 710-712. (Box 34, Folder 471)
      Caption title: ...Tu es enfant de Dieu M. Dors.
      On top of p. 1: 2 pages format E.F.
      On bottom of p. 1 in red ink: Copyright by Heugel 1934 H. 30917.
      With: pencil sketches on back for "Les filles de Bordeaux" and "Train du ciel." [David Drew].
    - [Marie Galante. Scène au dancing (Sketches)], [2] p. of music; 36 cm. R. 14, Fr. 706-708. (Box 34, Folder 469)
      With: sketches for "J'attends un navire."
    - [Marie Galante. Selections], 10 scores ([63] p.); 35 cm. R. 14, Fr. 713-747. (Box 34, Folder 472)
      Holograph signed, in ink and pencil with pencil markings.
      Contents: Introduction (7 p.). Les filles de Bordeaux ([1] p. crossed out, 8 p.). Marche de l'armée panaméenne ([7] p.). Intermezzo (4 p.). Introduction Dancing ([2] p.). [Tempo di Foxtrot] ([8] p.). J'attends un navire (12 p.). Le roi d'Aquitaine (6 p.). Le train du ciel (7 p.). Le grand Lustucru (4 p.).
    - Muschel von Margate
      See: Konjunktur. Muschel von Margate.
    - [Petroleuminseln. Lied von der braunen Inseln. Vocal score] Lied von der braunen Inseln / Kurt Weill; aus Feuchtenwangers Petroleuminseln, [1928 Nov.].; 1 score ([1] sheet); 42 cm. (Box 104, Folder 473)
    - [Petroleuminseln (Sketches)], [1] p. of music; 35 cm. R. 14, Fr. 748. (Box 34, Folder 474)
      Sketch on back: "Yankee Doodle."
    - Petroleum-Song
    - [We will never die. Libretto] We will never die / by Ben Hecht, [1943].; 28 shoots; 28 cm. (Box 34, Folder 475)
      Incidental music to pageant by Ben Hecht.
      Composed in 1943.
      "New script" - on title page.
      Contains Kurt Weill's annotations and names inscribed on title page.
    - [We will never die. Peace table (Sketches)] Peace table., 1 score ([7] p.); 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 750-754. (Box 34, Folder 476)
      For orchestra.
    - [We will never die. Rabbi's entrance (Sketches)], 1 score ([2] p.); 35 cm. R. 14, Fr. 755-756. (Box 34, Folder 476)
    - We will never die. Red army song.
      See: H. Arrangements. Knippera, L. [David Drew].
    - [We will never die (Sketches)], [14] sheets of music in various pagings; 40 cm. R. 14, Fr. 759-770. (Box 104, Folder 477)
      Contents: Intro Roll call ([1] sheet). Sabbath (Chanukah) (8 sheets). Exit 20 Rabbis (5 sheets).
    - [Your navy (Sketches)], [1942 Feb]; [11] p. of music; 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 771-777. (Box 34, Folder 478)
      Music for a radio program by Maxwell Anderson.
  - Orchestral, I.D
    - Concerto, violin, instrumental ensemble, op. 12., See also: H. Arrangements. [[Foxtrot and ragtime] (Sketches)]. [David Drew].
    - [Concerto, violin, instrumental ensemble, op. 12] Konzert für Violine u. Blasorchester = Concerto pour violon et orchestre d'instruments à vent: op. 12: Partitur / Kurt Weill, 1924 Apr.-May.; 1 score (96 sheets); 42 cm. (Box 104, Folder 479)
      Date at end.
    - [Concerto, violin, instrumental ensemble, op. 12. Short score] Konzert für Violine und Blasorchester: Ausgabe für Violine und Klavier, 1924 Apr.- May, c1925.; 1 short score (57 sheets); 42 cm. (Box 104, Folder 480)
      "Universal Edition Nr. 8339" - p. 1.
    - [Divertimento, men's voices, string quartet, orchestra, op. 5; arr.] Divertimento: 1922: für kleines Orchester mit Männerchor / Wieder-herstellung (1971) von David Drew. - c1971 by Lotte Lenya Weill-Detwiler and David Drew., 1 score (21, [10], 16 p.); 38 cm. (Box 34, Folder 481)
      Contents: I. Quasi maestoso. II. Andantino [not included]. III. Scherzo. IV. Choral.
    - [Divertimento, men's voices, string quartet, orchestra, op. 5. Choral] Schlusssatz aus dem Divertimento Op. 5 / v. Kurt Weill., 24 parts; 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 778-837. (Box 34, Folder 482)
      Includes 9 parts for men's voices and 15 parts for violin I-II, viola I-II, violoncello, double bass, horn, and trombone I-II.
      Note by David Drew on folder laid in.
    - [Divertimento, men's voices, string quartet, orchestra, op. 5 (Sketches)], pp. 7-14, [6] p. of music; 35 cm. R. 14, Fr. 837-845. (Box 34, Folder 482)
    - Fantasia, Passacaglia, and Hymnus
      See: Sinfonia sacra (Sketches).
    - [Kleine Dreigroschenmusik] Kleine Dreigroschen-Musik: für Blasorchester: Partitur / Kurt Weill, [1928 Dec.-1929 Jan.?] [David Drew].; 1 score (42 sheets); 42 cm. (Box 104, Folder 483)
      Suite from Dreigroschenoper for wind orchestra.
      Contents: 1) Die Ouvertüre, Nr. 2. Die Moritat vom Mackie Messer. Nr. 3. Der Anstatt dass-Song. Nr. 4. Die Ballade vom angenehmen Leben. Nr. 5. Polly's Lied. 5a) Die Tangoballade, Nr. 6. Der Kanonensong. Nr. 7. Dreigroschenmusik.
      See also: A. Operas, Operettas, Musicals, and Ballets. Dreigroschenoper.
    - Kleine Sinfonie
      See: Symphonies. no. 2.
    - Konzert für Violine und Blasorchester
      See: Concerto, violin, instrumental ensemble, op. 12.
    - Orchestersuite aus dem Pantomime Zaubernacht
      See: Quodlibet.
    - [Quodlibet] Quodlibet: Vier Orchesterstücke aus einer Kinder-pantomime: op. 9 / Kurt Weill, [1923].; 1 score (158 sheets); 42 cm. (Box 105, Folder 484)
      Orchestral suite freely adapted from Zaubernacht.
      On title page: An Albert Bing.
      On title page: U. E. 8348.
      See also: A. Operas, Operettas, Musicals, and Ballets. Zaubernacht.
    - Sinfonia sacra, See also: Divertimento, men's voices, string quartet, orchestra, op. 5 (Sketches). [David Drew].
    - [Sinfonia sacra; arr. (Sketches)], [1922].; [2] p. of music; 35 cm. R. 14, Fr. 846-847. (Box 34, Folder 485)
      Sketch of a piano part for an "arrangement for two pianos". [David Drew].
    - [Sinfonia sacra. Short score (Sketches)], Fantasia, Passacaglia u. Hymnus: Orchester.; [14] p. of music; 35 cm. R. 14, Fr. 847-855. (Box 34, Folder 485)
    - [Sinfonia sacra (Sketches)], [2] p. of music: 35 cm. R. 14, Fr. 856-857. (Box 34, Folder 485)
      Setting of "Ich will ihn preisen" from Rilke's Das Stundenbuch [David Drew].
      See also: G. Chamber and Instrumental. Quartets, strings, op. 8.
    - [Symphonies, no. 1] First Symphony / by Kurt Weill, 1921 Apr.-Jun.; 1 score (64 p.); 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 858-890. (Box 34, Folder 486)
      Dated: April-Juni 1921.
      On p. 1 in blue ink: First symphony by Kurt Weill... copyright by Karoline Weill-Davis May 7th 1955 New York.
    - [Symphonies, no. 1] First symphony / Kurt Weill., 39 parts; 34 cm. (Box 34, Folder 487-489)
      Manuscript in copyist's hand (photocopies).
      Includes flute I-II, oboe, clarinet I-II/bass clarinet, bassoon I-II, horn I-II, trumpet, trombone, percussion (3), violin 1 (5), violin II (4), violin III (4), viola 1 (3), viola II (2), violoncello I (2), violoncello II (2), double bass I (2). and double bass II.
    - [Symphonies, no. 1; arr.], 19 [i.e. 20] sheets of music; 33 cm. (Box 34, Folder 486)
      Arrangement for piano, 4 hands.
      Primo and secundo parts on alternate pages.
    - [Symphonies, no. 2] Kleine Sinfonie: Nachtstücke 1933 / Kurt Weill., [1933-1934].; 1 score (99 p.); (Box 34, Folder 490)
      Caption title: à Madame la Princesse Edmond de Polignac.
      "Commissioned by and dedicated to Madame la Princesse Edmond de Polignac, autograph owned by the heirs of the Princess" - Kowalke.
      See also: F. Songs. Abschiedsbrief; Es regnet; and Grande complainte de Fantômas (Sketches). [David Drew].
  - Large-scale Vocal, I.E
    - Arbeiter Chöre
      See: Zu Potsdam unter den Eichen.
    - Ballade vom ertrunkenen Mädchen
      See: Berliner Requiem. Ballade.
    - Beat! Beat! Drums, See also: F. Songs. Walt Whitman songs.
    - [Beat! Beat! Drums; arr. Vocal score] Beat Beat Drums / music by Kurt Weill; Walt Whitman, c1942.; 1 vocal score (10 p.); 34 cm. R. 15, Fr. 1-7. (Box 35, Folder 491)
      Piano-vocal arrangement for speaker, chorus, and orchestra.
      "One of [Four Patriotic Melodramas] commissioned by Helen Hayes and Victor Records for Fight for Freedom Inc." - David Drew.
      Composed in 1942 Mar. [David Drew].
    - [Beat! Beat! Drums; arr. Vocal score] Beat Beat Drums / music by Kurt Weill; Walt Whitman., 1 vocal score (10 p.); 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 7-13. (Box 35, Folder 491)
      "Black and white song" and pencil sketches on title page.
      Page 9 in crossed out.
    - [Beat! Beat! Drums; arr. Vocal score (Sketches)] Beat! Beat! Drums / music by Kurt Weill; Walt Whitman., 1 vocal score (2 p.); 34 cm. R. 14, Fr. 13-14. (Box 35, Folder 491)
    - [Berliner Requiem. Ballade. Text] Ballade vom ertrunkenen Mädchen., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 35, Folder 492)
    - [Berliner Requiem. Ballade. Text. English & German] Vom ertrunkenen Mädchen., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 35, Folder 492)